because I have a federal felony
conviction,
I lost my gun rights for life.
Well, the governor of Virginia, when I
got out of prison,
uh Governor Terry McAuliffe,
God bless this man,
I had not even applied for a state
pardon because I hadn't committed a
state crime, but he followed my case, he
thought I'd been wronged, and he issued
me a pardon.
It was symbolic,
but it technically reinstated my state
gun rights, but I still don't have my
federal gun rights.
So, if I go out to the Dulles Expo
Center on Saturday to the gun show,
which is there every weekend,
>> Yeah.
>> and I buy [clears throat] a gun, I'm
perfectly within my rights, according to
the state of Virginia.
But,
at the federal level,
a felon with a gun is a mandatory
minimum 5-year sentence. I could get 8
years
>> Wow.
>> just for being in possession of a gun.
>> Do you think you're still watched now,
waiting for you to trip up so that they
so that I I probably didn't want to I do
want to ask this. Do you think you're
still getting watched now and waiting
for you to do anything, to slip up,
anything? Or
have you got to such a point now where
they're worried about maybe the
influence that you have, and also the
intelligence that you have, because you
clearly won a lot of case, you know, won
a lot of stuff
from the prison, well letters from
Loretta.
>> I did. You know, I I'm very proud to say
that a few weeks ago the director of the
Federal Bureau of Prisons called me and
asked me if I would serve on an informal
advisory council
to advise him on how to reform the
Bureau of Prisons.
>> Wow.
>> I said, "Absolutely yes." I said,
"But I don't think you're going to
succeed." I said, "Your problem is
corruption. You guys are corrupt from
the very top to the very bottom and
everybody in between, and the first
thing you're going to have to do, and
I'm saying this as a lifelong union
member and pro-union activist, the first
thing you're going to have to do is to
break that union."
>> Wow.
>> Cuz all it does is support corruption.
And you'll never get it done, let alone
done in the next 2 and 1/2 years.
>> What did he say?
>> He said, "You're probably right, but
let's meet and talk about it."
>> Yeah.
>> He started off the conversation by
saying, "You've been talking [__] about
the Bureau of Prisons for the last 10
years." I said, "Correction, I've been
talking [__] about the Bureau of Prisons
for the last 13 years."
>> to say, "And rightly so." I said,
>> And I said, "Because the whole system is
corrupt and broken."
>> Do you know what? There was There's
times
we were driving down the roads and there
were some of them had happened and then
the Bureau of Prisons would screw you
over and you didn't get your You didn't
get out and my wife would go,
"Those bastards! I can't believe they
did that." She never swears or anything,
you know. She's like, "Oh my god, that's
horrible." You know, she'd go nuts.
>> They're horrible. They really are.
>> Believe it. And And this And this is the
problem and I think, you know, where
does this start? And here's the thing
that I want to do is is
not I mean
just what we can do even we have lawyer
with different, you know, hundreds of
lawyers that are that are maybe
listening to this listen to this podcast
in our network. Maybe something's going
to tweak that they can start to look at
this change, but you're saying there's
probably not going to be change.
>> No.
I don't think they'll there will be
change.
>> What would you like to see in What would
be an ideal situation for you, John, for
the transformation of the prison reform?
What would you think would What's the
minimal thing you're saying would change
the direction of it?
>> Of the Bureau of Prisons? I If If you
could handle corruption, if you could
address corruption, it would change
everything.
But there are so many different moving
parts involved in addressing corruption.
>> Uh
>> First of all,
the only qualifications to be a a prison
guard in the United States prison guard
now
>> correctional officer
>> A prison guard?
>> is you have to be
at least working on a GED. You don't
even need a high school education, just
working on a GED and no felony
convictions. That's it.
Um there's a rule in the Bureau of
Prisons that prisoners may not hand out
the mail.
But the prisoners always hand out the
mail. Do you know why?
>> No, why? Cuz they don't
>> Cuz the guards can't read.
>> Come on.
>> The guards can't read.
>> Serious.
>> And so they can't hand out the mail. So
the prisoners do it.
It's that bad.
>> It's that bad.
>> There there was something that happened
when I was at Loretto, FCI Loretto,
where um
the there's a minimum security camp
across the street, and you're sort of on
your honor not to run away, and you have
to follow the rules. Well, some of these
prisoners, against the rules,
got some money, you're not allowed to
have cash, and they ordered a pizza.
And um
when the pizza man came to drop off the
pizza,
he knows that there were other prisoners
who were in the woods walking away from
the prison.
So he went across the street to the
actual prison and said, "Listen, I'm the
pizza delivery guy,
and not only did your prisoners order
pizzas,
but there were a couple of other
prisoners
who um
were walking away. They're walking down
the highway."
And the guards ran down there and caught
them.
They almost instantly hired the pizza
delivery man
to be a guard.
His only qualification was that he had
two eyes, and they both worked.
And he could read, apparently.
And so he's the new prison guard.
>> So do you think that that there should
be changed to
how prison guards are hired and and
trained?
>> Oh, yeah, I do. I think there should be
there should be huge changes.
Uh for example,
uh they're they're grotesquely
underpaid.
>> Mhm.
>> I I was being taken out
to um
to a um
an orthopedist. I had broken my pinky
finger.
So uh
>> Oh, yeah, I remember you saying that in
the book.
>> Yeah, actually it was this pinky finger.
Yeah, I broke my pinky finger. There So
they they chained me, shackled me, my
ankles, around my waist, my wrists,
everything. I'm shackled. I can take a
little baby step at a time.
And um
And uh
they put me in the van
and one of them
they were two two in the in the front, a
driver and passenger. And one of them
said, "I got passed over for a promotion
again."
And the other one said, "You still
haven't gotten that four?" And like it's
any of my business, I said, "You're a
GS4?"
He said, "No, I got a I got passed over
for a four. I'm a three."
I said, "How do you
feed yourself?"
And he said, "Why?"
He's making at the time, this is 10
years ago, he's probably making 20 or
22,000 dollars a year.
>> Oh, jeez.
>> And I He said, "Why? What were you?" I
said, "I was a 15 and so was my wife.
And we still had trouble making ends
meet."
>> What the hell?
>> A three. It's no wonder they all live in
this trailer park up the road from the
from the prison and then they're
bragging, "Well, I have a double wide.
You only have a single wide."
Yeah, I mean, this is how bad it is.
>> I don't understand.
>> But getting back to the issue of
corruption, um and this is something
that I told the the BOP uh director
was, you know, when
when the commissary gets a shipment of
Pop-Tarts, like an entire pallet of
Pop-Tarts, we're talking about 5,000
dollars worth of Pop-Tarts.
>> Yeah.
>> And then the guard backs up his Ford
F-150 pickup truck and loads the entire
pallet onto the pickup truck and takes
it back to his double wide and sells it
on Facebook Marketplace or on eBay.
That's unacceptable.
>> That is unacceptable.
>> with 10,000 dollars worth of batteries.
Or with, you know,
extension cords or, you know, bags of
tuna or whatever. They steal everything.
>> Because they're because they're
untrained and they're undisciplined and
they don't have any
>> And and they're underpaid.
>> And they're underpaid because they need
to survive.
>> Yeah. That was it.
>> That's crazy. Do you So
you mentioned as well in your book that
there's a big problem in the in in
health.
>> Huge.
>> Right? And I think that's another thing
that the
the beauty of prisons need to look at
because that was a few other you know
shocking moments that you know made my
wife scream.
Um
>> Yeah.
>> The way you were treated with just even
your your own your your pink key and
other people were treated people and I
have to say as well John I mean it was
quite shocking. People dying that didn't
need to die.
>> Yeah.
It happened all the time.
>> They they don't
not treated like human beings and this
is a big issue in the prisons.
>> And then you have the warden
going to a terminally ill patient and
saying if you sign a document promising
not to sue us, we'll let you go and die
at home.
And he said no and he died in in a steel
bunk all alone.
>> Do you feel that
Did you get any backlash about your book
from the prison service when I got I had
to ask this because you didn't hold back
like you freaking let them rip.
>> And I told them bring it because I'm not
afraid of you.
>> Wow.
>> The warden repeatedly threatened me with
solitary. Repeatedly.
And I laughed at him once. We were
standing in the hall right by the the
mail room
and he told me if you don't stop writing
this book, I'm going to put you in
solitary and I'm not going to let you
out. And I said, "Oh please." I told
him. I said, "Warden
I've gone nose to nose with Al-Qaeda,
with Hezbollah, with the Iranians and
I'm supposed to be afraid of you?"
>> I just
>> [laughter]
>> yeah.
>> Please. I said, "Give me a little
credit." I said, "I lived in Yemen
>> Yeah.
>> Pakistan, Afghanistan. I'm not afraid of
Loretto, Pennsylvania."
>> Wow. Do you think that it was
Do you think they were frightened of you
then?
>> Yeah. Well I I'll tell you why.
So my best friend was an Italian, Mark.
And
>> didn't have a lot of yeah you didn't
have a lot
>> I just talked to him yesterday. He's
He's like a brother like a brother to
me.
And so um
So Mark was talking to the one guard
that everybody hated the most. Not me, I
never had any interaction with this guy.
He stayed on his side of the fence and I
stayed on mine. But um he went by the by
the nickname Blue. He was the only
person that covered up his name tag with
with masking tape. He didn't want
anybody to know his name.
He was also the only guard that wore a
stab vest because he was so cruel, he
was afraid somebody was going to
legitimately take a shot at him and
stabbing him.
>> So Mark was talking to Blue one day
and he said, "Blue, where are you going
to be for the next uh quarter?" And he
said, "Oh, I'm going to be over in
Central 1 unit." And Mark said, "My
friend John is in Central 1." And Blue
said, "The CIA guy? I never mess with
that guy."
And Mark said, "Really? Why?"
And he said, "That's all I need. I work
8 hours here and then I go out to my car
and CNN standing next to it? No,
thanks."
>> Jeez.
>> So what I did is I filed a Freedom of
Information Act request on myself.
Much to my surprise, I got it 6 weeks
later. It was mostly garbage. It was 250
pages. About 20 pages were
important.
And there was one from several days
before I arrived in the prison. It was a
memo from the warden to all employees
and it said subject
arriving inmate John Kiriakou. And then
in these giant block letters, it just
says caution
inmate has access to the media.
>> I think though that was a blessing for
you. I mean, I'm listening and I'm like
you if he didn't have that access, if he
wasn't in the media, his life would have
been worse. He would have been They
would It would have been like a Russian
gulag.
>> Without a without a doubt.
Without a doubt.
>> would have disappeared essentially,
gone.
>> Yep.
>> So I think I think your media presence
was the the And who knows? Maybe it is
going to be the thing that that will
help to change, especially now that
you're talking with uh, the director of
prisons. What do you think the the What
do you think lawyers need to try and
understand from your case and from your
history? Your experiences there because
it seems to me that the lawyers really
don't understand that they don't know
enough of what's going on.
>> They don't.
>> there to fight a case and that's it. But
should they be getting more involved?
>> Oh, I think they should. I'll give you
another example, a very recent example.
Um, about 3 weeks ago, Senator Mike Lee
went on to X, Twitter.
And he said that a constituent of his in
Utah
called his office in a panic because
they had a son in the Bureau of Prisons
and
the son all of a sudden just dropped out
of contact. Uh,
emails aren't being answered. Nobody at
the prison will give any information.
So, Senator Lee
picked up the phone and called the
prison
and said,
"I'm Senator Mike Lee of Utah. I'm
calling about my constituent so-and-so."
>> Yeah.
>> And the voice on the other end at the
prison says, "You have a lot of [__]
nerve calling here." and hung up on him.
A sitting US Senator.
>> That's crazy.
>> So, I tweeted at him and I said,
"Senator, I think I can help you on
this."
I got a call minutes later from his
chief of staff.
And I said, "I think the constituent is
in something called diesel therapy."
"What is that?"
>> Yeah, I never
>> the guy asks. And I said, "Whenever a
prisoner is deemed to be a problem, like
me, I was a problem, and they threatened
me with diesel therapy.
>> Right.
>> do
I'll I'll give you a a a made-up example
starting at FCI Loretto where I was.
>> Yeah.
>> They'll take you to Loretto
from Loretto and they put you on the
prison bus.
And the prison bus goes to a prison in a
maximum security prison in northeastern
Pennsylvania where you just sit and wait
for the next transfer. And then from
there, they take you to Harrisburg. From
Harrisburg, they put you on Conair.
You know, the the BOP
>> move
>> around. So, you're you're literally
you're not traceable. You're just
>> Because when you're in what's called
transportation status,
you're not permitted access to a phone,
>> Or to
>> or to even a pen and paper.
And literally no one has any idea where
you are. And they can keep you in
transportation status for years.
Transfer you to Atlanta, from Atlanta to
Oklahoma City, Oklahoma City to Yankton,
South Dakota, South Dakota to Las Vegas,
Las Vegas to Lompoc.
They'll they'll just transfer you
every couple of days, every couple of
weeks, for the rest of your sentence.
And nobody has any idea where you are.
>> Wow.
>> Because they know they can get away with
it.
And so, we need lawyers to like step up,
file injunctions, flood the courts, make
the BOP respond.
They have to put an end to it.
>> I've noticed that. They I don't seem to
do it. I've got a friend of mine who's a
criminal lawyer. And
>> Because there's no money involved.
>> Huh?
>> There's no money involved. Poor people
can't pay legal bills.
>> See, that's the problem. And again, it
boils down to this it boils down to
money.
>> Yeah.
>> It boils down to business, and they
can't defend themselves.
>> I you know what? I I think the same.
>> A lot of people go that are Yeah, I
might get it. Look, prisons are there
for a reason. If you're a really bad guy
and you [__] up, you're going to go in
and you're going to be right.
>> There are some people who go society
needs to be protected.
>> Yeah.
>> Pedophiles, the murderers, the violent
people, the rapists, the drug
traffickers. Yeah. We need to be
protected from those people. Sure.
>> Absolutely. I would agree with that. But
there's a lot of people that don't.
>> That's right.
>> A lot. And they don't get any reform.
And I don't see the law the lawyers need
to make more of a noise
>> Yes.
>> about it.
And that doesn't seem to be that doesn't
seem to be happening.
What was it? Your your law firm or your
lawyers? You mean you obviously have a
great
respect for them.
>> I was blessed. They were giants. They
really were.
>> helping I mean, I don't always say Are
they still helping you now or or
>> No,
I mean, thank God, knock on wood. I
don't I don't need any help. We're still
in touch. We get together periodically
for lunch. I lecture at their law school
classes. One teaches at
Georgetown and other at American
University School of Law. Um so yeah,
we're and I've referred a half a dozen
cases to them. They're they're giants.
One has passed away.
Two of the others are semi-retired,
nearing retirement. Um
but but we're still in touch.
These guys were were giants in my life.
>> Did they recognize the same problems in
the industry in in in the legal in
Yes, and they never did they ever voice
it to you during like look look what
this is screwed up. This is this is bad,
but there's nothing you can do.
>> Constantly, yes. Constantly. And and
because they recognized the problems,
that's why they were criminal defense
attorneys.
They took this all very very seriously.
>> Yeah. But how did you
cope mentally with your mental health?
>> You know,
it's funny. I I thought I was going to
>> to a minimum security work camp. That's
what the judge said.
>> told me that at the beginning, yeah. And
actually we were told
>> Yeah.
>> I thought I'm just going to, you know,
keep my mouth shut, do my time, go home.
And then they put me in the actual
prison
to to further punish me. And so I
I hadn't really prepared to protect
myself mentally. I was just kind of
thrown in it.
>> Yeah.
>> On the very first day that I was in the
prison, I'd only been in the prison for
about 5 hours, and there was mail call.
And a lady had sent me a postcard with a
rose on it.
Um a lady from Ringgold, Georgia who had
followed my case.
And um and I thought, what a thoughtful
thing to do.
I don't even know this woman.
And she took time out of her day to send
me this postcard. And I made a decision
that very first day that I was going to
respond to every letter that I received.
Not realizing I was going to end up
answering
7,000 letters
to 675 different people.
But I did. So there were two things that
passed the time for me and it was
writing letters, lots and lots of
letters.
And writing Doing Time Like a Spy.
Longhand, which won two literary awards,
crazy enough.
>> honestly I you you did that longhand
actually. You wrote that longhand.
>> And you know what? I had to do it twice.
Because the guards seized the
manuscripts. They said it was a threat
to the public safety and they destroyed
it.
>> yeah you said that in the book actually.
Your manuscript had disappeared.
>> Yeah. They destroyed it.
>> Do you think you'll do a follow-up with
the book?
>> Pardon?
>> Do you think you'll do a follow-up with
that book?
>> No. And I'll tell you why. I would
I I've written in 10 books now. That was
my second.
But I've recently been signed by the
Creative Artists Agency, CAA.
>> Yeah.
>> And they told me
in very clear English, you're going to
write fiction from now on.
>> Oh dude, you definitely
>> [laughter]
>> Yes. Right. Okay. I get it. That And
that's probably that's straight up your
alley actually.
>> I'm a little intimidated by it but I I
I've got 10,000 words done and
>> look if John le Carré can do it
let's face it.
>> I'm going to give it a shot.
>> He had the he had the history. He was
with the service.
>> Yep.
>> And and did the same thing as you know
many other people do. Yeah I think that
would be probably brilliant actually for
>> to try. I'm going to try. I think I can
do it. My goal My goal is to have
100,000 words by the end of the year but
it it's hard. I'm going to try.
>> Dude, that's awesome. Yeah I've written
books myself actually and so I know how
hard it is and I lost two manuscripts as
I was writing them. I was [snorts]
writing it I was writing a book and
I was tied to
Simon & Schuster and another one and
Atria Books and and I was writing two
manuscripts at the same time. Don't ever
freaking do that. Especially when you
get the blue screen of death and then
you lose a manuscript. That's
>> Oh my god.
>> And then I sent I sent
I sent the manuscript in for one and I
sent another one in and then they ended
up coming back saying
I "I don't think this chapter should be
in this book." I'd mixed up the chapters
from each book and put them in sent them
in. So, I was a total freaking screw up.
So, I get it, but I think it was
freaking awesome that you're doing that.
>> I'm trying. It's hard work.
>> So, did you do any legal stuff from you
I mean when you were in
in prison you had time? It seemed to me
that you were studying a lot as well.
>> I was. I did I did two things.
Um
there was a Mexican drug cartel member
in my cell who asked me if I was
educated when I first arrived and I
said, "Yes."
And he said, "Um would you write my
appeal?" I said, "Well, I'm not a
lawyer."
"Well, yeah, but you're educated."
I said, "Yeah, you know what? You're
right. How hard could it be to write an
appeal?"
So, he gave me his case papers. He was
completely totally utterly guilty.
Plus, you know, when you get into a gun
fight with the DEA and they catch you in
the cocaine warehouse and you're
bleeding out there. Yeah, you're guilty.
>> You're guilty. You can't you can't you
know, you can't get away with that. You
can't lie your way out of that.
>> No. So, I I wrote the appeal. It was all
based on technicalities.
The the appellate court acknowledged the
technicalities, but they weren't they
weren't important enough to have changed
the outcome of the case. So, so we lost.
But, he told the other cartel members
that I was a good guy, that I did his
appeal and that I didn't charge him
anything. He offered me He offered me
money in the form of of you know, bagged
fish, which is currency.
I said, "No, no, no. I I have people on
the outside. They they put money in my
commissary account. I'm good."
And so, he told everybody that I was a
good guy and I didn't charge him. And
then near the very end of my um
I'm very proud of this. Near the very
end of my
uh sentence
I happen to be in Mark's
cell.
We would We would have dinner and we
would hang out until it was uh
recall where everybody's got to got to
go back to their own cells.
And um
so, I'm reading the USA Today and there
was an article about the the Second
Chance Act. It It had just been signed
into law and I said, "Buddy, did you
read this article?"
And he said, "Nah, not really."
I said, "This article's about you."
"What do you mean?" He says.
And I said, "If you have a draconian
sentence
and if you if you had committed the same
crime today and you would have gotten a
lighter sentence,
you can appeal."
And I said he said, "I I don't even know
how I would do that." I said, "I'll do
it."
So, I wrote the appeal and I sent it to
the Justice Department
and um
you have to send it to Justice and then
Justice would submit it uh to the courts
and then I was released
in February.
In August, his mother called me and she
was crying.
And I answered the phone and I said, "Oh
my god, what happened to him?"
I thought something terrible had
happened.
And she said,
"They're letting him go.
You won that appeal."
>> Wow, I think you mentioned it in your
book, didn't you? At the end of it.
>> I couldn't believe it. And they let him
go.
>> You either mentioned that in your book
or you mentioned a podcast that I
listened to. Yeah, one or the other.
>> I'm I'm very happy to say Mark
is now literally the most successful
real estate agent on the New Jersey
Shore.
>> Is he really?
>> Yeah.
>> Do you know what? He's a classic example
of how someone can go into an
incarcerated life and come out and
actually come out the other side and be
successful.
>> He should have never been in prison in
the first place.
You know, this is something I also that
I said in the book that there's this
there's this joke that's ongoing joke
that everybody in prison's innocent.
Well, you know what? A lot of people in
prison are innocent.
>> No, I would I believe that. I believe
there's a lot of people going
unnecessarily.
>> But if you've got 50 years hanging over
your head and they're offering you two,
you know, in the words of one of my
attorneys, this can be the a blip in
your life if or it can be the defining
event in your life. Make it the blip.
Take the deal.
>> You think it was the it was probably
it's a hard I know you I know you're
going to say, but this was a blessing
for you in the end.
>> Well, my brother told me
on the day of my arrest he said, "I know
you can't possibly see this right now,
but this is going to turn out to be the
best thing that ever happened to you."
And it did sound insane when he said it,
but it turned out to be true.
>> Now, you mentioned a couple of times you
were suicidal. Was that before you went
in or when you were in there?
>> Before.
Yeah.
>> How did you How How did that Is that
because you were There's an element
of grief I'm kind of well-known for
dealing with and helping people cope
with grief.
So, what There's an element there
obviously that I see that obviously you
were grieving what was in the life that
you had.
>> It was
it was the prospect of dying in prison.
>> Really, yeah.
>> 45 years. I mean, 45 We can't There's
There's There's no wiggle room there. 45
>> anticipating that that was the end.
>> That was it.
>> Wow.
>> 45 years. And they stuck with that for
10 months. 45 years. Take a plea, sure,
45 years. Don't take a plea, you're
still getting 45 years.
>> Wow.
>> Mhm.
>> How did you How did you
get over that hump that I'm going to
fight that
>> My wife told me
"They have consistently underestimated
your resolve.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> You're far tougher than they think you
are and you can fight this." And my
lawyers, they wanted to go to trial. We
talked about it until literally the last
minute.
And uh I I was fully prepared to go to
trial.
And oh my god,
I might have accidentally said some of
the horrible crimes against humanity and
war crimes that I witnessed in 15 years
at the CIA while on the stand testifying
on my own behalf.
>> Mhm. They didn't want that.
>> They didn't want that.
>> No.
I I I I I I know
that
other other agencies and other places of
the world didn't think that was the
right thing either.
>> That's right.
>> And And that was And that was a big
>> You know what?
I I just happened to to have this I was
recently given the highest award
that the Irish government bestows.
They've given one gold medal per year
since 1777.
And of the last seven recipients, the
last eight recipients, it's the
president of Ireland, the president of
Finland, five Nobel Peace Prize winners,
>> Wow.
>> The the government of Luxembourg gave me
a medal for truth-telling.
I'm I'm celebrated in Greece and in
Iceland
and and elsewhere.
It's the It's the United States that's
wrong on these issues. Other countries
recognize it.
>> John, why didn't you leave? Why did you
stay in America? I suppose that's a a
loaded question.
>> Well, I've got five kids here and uh
>> Well, that's obviously Yeah, that's
true.
>> Yeah, and my my wife is here. I'm I'm
proud to say that I've become a dual
US-Greek citizen. I vote I vote in
Greece.
>> Right.
>> I hope to buy some property in Greece by
the end of the year. And I'm going to
split my time. But damn it, this is my
country. I'm not going to let them force
me out of it.
>> You are very patriotic, contrary to what
a lot of people say. You come across to
me from from someone who's a Scotsman
who's coming from the UK, I do see you
as very patriotic.
>> What do you mean contrary to what some
people say?
>> Well, a lot of people will What's that?
Some people will say
There's that whole idea he's a traitor
he's a he's he's a he's a you know, he
loves America. And I think that's unfair
where people label you wrong cuz you're
definitely a patriot.
>> only morons
>> Yeah, that's true.
>> Yeah, say stupid things like that. You
know, the it Treason I've I've actually
written about this a couple of times
because treason is specifically defined
in the Constitution.
It's providing aid and comfort to the
enemy in a time of war.
Period. We throw around that word
treason, traitor all the time. And it
it's become meaningless.
>> It has.
>> And I'll put I'll put my record and
reputation up against anybody's,
anybody's in America.
>> I think I I I've got to get you back on
this cuz I'd love to dive into the
whistleblower side of things for the
legal industry cuz I think that's
>> There's a lot to say.
>> I have to get you back. If you will if
you will come back on I'd love to talk
about that and maybe even get get some
lawyers on because I think that's a
that's a big thing. Do you think I mean
you have had now you're enjoying success
and you may be a catalyst to potential
change.
>> I hope so. I hope.
>> I hope.
Do you think that Do you think you're
going to have any any potential power to
change anything because of your infamy
now and and you know the way that you've
>> If I do if there is going to be change
it will be only because of this
infamy that I've developed. I somebody
told me the other day
that they saw a marketing study saying
that I am the most
popular person in America among males
between 15 and 30.
>> Really?
>> Yeah, like where did that come from?
>> Do you think you're going to end up in
GQ magazine at some point?
>> I I did a thing for GQ three months ago.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm embracing it.
People listen to me because I tell the
truth.
And so I'm running with it.
>> Josh what my wife said. My wife is no
fool. And my wife said when she listened
to she said he's speaking from the heart
and he's telling the truth.
>> I'm trying my best.
>> And you can tell everybody else has got
different agendas.
And I think yeah you definitely
you've definitely got a lot to say and I
think your experiences John have been
absolutely phenomenal. And um
I do want to get you back on. There's a
lot that we can talk about on on Help
Lawyer and I think there's there's
a lot of our lawyers will be really
interested to see this. I think we've
definitely got to do more about the
whistleblower thing cuz I think there's
going to be more of it. A lot more of
it.
>> There is a lot to say and I think
there's a lot to say that lawyers
especially would be interested in.
>> Yeah, definitely. I think this is um
this this has been awesome just having a
general a chat to get to know you and uh
let everybody know what you're up what
you're up to and and and how they can
read your books and stuff like
>> Thank you for that. I've got a whole
bunch of books
uh
out and coming out. There's one coming
out next month, one coming out the month
after. Uh they're all on Amazon. Just go
to John Kiriakou books and it they'll
all pop right up. But I'm also starting
a new podcast in just the next 2 and 1/2
weeks on YouTube. It's called uh John
Kiriakou's Briefing Room. And I'm really
proud to say
that I've got a podcast
we're just finishing the third the
second season. Uh it's on Apple Podcasts
and Spotify called John Kiriakou's Dead
Drop.
>> I got We listened to it.
>> It's crazy popular. I can't believe We
get these numbers in the morning and I'm
like, "You've got to be kidding me."
>> just started I mean Joe and I we
finished your book and we started
another book and Joe was like, "Ah, this
is a book but not one of your books." It
was another book. She says, "This is
boring. There's not something else." And
we got another one and Joe was like,
"Okay." I said, "Well, I've got Dead
Drop. Let's get it." Uh so downloaded it
and she loved the stories of you in
Greece and your mother and all this
stuff cuz she loves to hear about the
stories. So so we've been listening to
Dead Drop.
>> Thank you.
And Apple Podcasts likes it so much they
asked me to do a different one in season
3. They wanted me to do they're calling
it um
Oh, um The Spy's Guide to
So I'm going to I'm going to do The
Spy's Guide to London, Paris, Vienna,
Athens, Abu Dhabi, Tokyo, Bangkok.
Go all over the world. Tourists see a
city one way, spies see it in a
completely different way. So we'll do
each city from a spy's perspective.